Preliminary Inventory to the George Davis Herron Papers, 1916-1927
Hoover Institution Archives
- BOUND VOLUMES (on shelf)
  - Volume IV. Austria-2
    - House to Herron. Disclaiming any part in Austrian Peace Treaty and disapproving the same, 1919 September 7 (Item LXXXVIII)
    - Telegram of Vorarlberg Commissioners to President Wilson, sent through Herron, 1919 September 8 (Item LXXXIX)
    - Telegram from Herron to Schlesinger. Changing appointment concerning Vorarlberg matter, 1919 September 12 (Item XC)
    - Herron to Klein. Inquiry as to Austrian censorship, 1919 September 23 (Item XCI)
    - Herron to House. Enclosing appeal sent by Professor Lammasch concerning Austrian prisoners in Siberia, 1919 September 24 (Item XCII)
    - German original of appeal referred to above, 1919 September 24 (Item XCIII)
    - Translation of foregoing appeal (Item XCIII A)
    - House to Herron. Concerning appeal of Lammasch; impossibility of getting satisfactory action, 1919 September 16 (Item XCIV)
    - Lammasch to Herron. Concerning conditions of the intellectuals in Austria, 1919 October 18 (Item XCV)
    - Lammasch to Herron, 1919 October 21 (Item XCVI)
    - Herron to House, 1919 October 21 (Item XCVII)
    - Lammasch to Herron, 1919 October 25 (Item XCVIII)
    - Herron to Lammasch, 1919 October 27 (Item XCIX)
    - Herron to House. Giving copy of letter from Lammasch, 1919 October 27 (Item C)
    - Herron to House. Enclosing Memorandum by Professor Karmin, 1919 October 28 (Item CI)
    - Memorandum of Karmin sent to House. On Austrian conditions; German danger; an entire province for sale (Item CII)
    - Continuation of above (Item CIII)
    - Whitehouse to Herron. Concerning Lammasch letters, 1919 October 29 (Item CIV)
    - Herron to Whitehouse. Same, 1919 November 10 (Item CV)
    - Herron to Whitehouse. Enclosing Lammasch Memorandum, 1919 November 10 (Item CVI)
    - Herron to Trevelyan. Enclosing Lammasch memorandum, 1919 November 10 (Item CVII)
    - Herron to Charles R. Crane. Replying to a letter concerning Dr. Dillon, and enclosing Lammasch memorandum, 1919 November 10 (Item CVIII)
    - Herron to House. Enclosing Lammasch memorandum, 1919 November 10 (Item CIX)
    - Memorandum of Lammasch mentioned above (Item CIX A)
    - Herron to House. Enclosing appeal of Mayor of Vienna, 1919 December 2 (Item CX)
    - Herron to Vanderlip. Same, 1919 December 2 (Item CX A)
    - Herron to Crane. Same, 1919 December 2 (Item CX B)
    - Appeal of Mayor of Vienna referred to in preceding letters (Item CX C)
    - Herron to Vanderlip. Conditions in Vienna and Austria; suggesting visit of Dr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1919 December 9 (Item CXI)
    - Herron to William A. White, 1920 January 7 (Item CXII)
    - Dr. Felix Weiser to Herron. Concerning proposed Austrian Mission to America; asking for introductions; conditions in Austria, 1920 February 6 (Item CXIII)
    - Herron to Weiser. Enclosing letters of introduction and discussing failure to obtain credit for $150,000,000, 1920 February 14 (Item CXIV)
    - Herron to George M. Reynolds. Introducing Dr. Weiser (Item CXIV A)
    - Herron to Charles R. Crane. Same (Item CXIV B)
    - Other letters. Same (Item CXIV C)
    - Weiser to Herron, 1920 February 28 (Item CXV)
    - Weiser to Herron. His resignation from Government; Austrian League of Nations Union; international law library, 1920 April 25 (Item CXVI)
    - Austrian League of Nations Union to Herron, 1920 July 5 (Item CXVII)
  - Volume V. Hungary, Czechoslovakia
    - Professor Singer to Herron. Conditions in Austro-Hungary; Czecho-Slovaks action; Magyars and other nationalities in Hungary, 1918 October 22 (Item I)
    - Translation of preceding letter (Item I A)
    - Herron to State Department, 1918 October 24 (Item II)
    - Herron to Singer, 1918 October 25 (Item III)
    - Singer to Herron. Arrival in Switzerland of Czech Delegation; Austro-Hungarian problems. In German, 1918 October 28 (Item IV)
    - Singer to Herron. Regarding Czech Delegation; and Dr. Furber. In German, 1918 November 1 (Item IV A)
    - Herron to Singer, 1918 November 3 (Item V)
    - Lazlo Havas to Herron. Regarding injustice of settlement to Hungary; misinformation; suggested tour of investigation, 1918 November 19 (Item VI)
    - Herron to Havas. Visit of Count Windisch-Graetz; America's desire for justice for all people; suggested tour, 1918 November 21 (Item VII)
    - Herron to State Department, 1918 November 23 (Item VIII)
    - Havas to Herron, 1918 November 27 (Item IX)
    - Herron to Havas. Concerning principles of nationalities, 1918 December 2 (Item X)
    - Havas to Herron. Urging Herron to come to Hungary to see conditions for himself, 1918 December 4 (Item XI)
    - Herron to Havas. Concerning reconstruction of Hungary, 1918 December 5 (Item XI A)
    - Herron to State Department, 1918 December 6 (Item XII)
    - Havas to Herron, 1918 December 6 (Item XIII)
    - Herron to State Department. Concerning Havas and Hungarian situation, 1918 December 9 (Item XIV)
    - Stovall to Herron. Suggested appointment of a better qualified and more acceptable representative than Mme. Schwimmer, 1918 December 9 (Item XV)
    - Herron to Stovall. Meeting with Mr. Havas; Hungarian representative at Berne; transmission of letter to America, 1918 December 12 (Item XVI)
    - Havas to Herron, 1918 December 13 (Item XVII)
    - Herron to Peace Commissioners, 1918 December 15 (Item XVIII)
    - Herron to Havas. Concerning requested visit of Herron to Hungary and request of Hungarian Government for a premature reply to Wilson, 1918 December 15 (Item XIX)
    - Stovall to Herron. Concerning transmission of a Hungarian letter to Washington, 1918 December 17 (Item XX)
    - Herron to Havas. Same subject as above, 1918 December 19 (Item XXI)
    - Stovall to Herron. Acknowledging letter of December 16, report sent to Peace Mission; illness of Mr. Wilson, 1918 December 29 (Item XXII)
    - Havas to Herron, 1918 December 20 (Item XXIII)
    - Herron to Peace Commissioners, 1918 December 21 (Item XXIV)
    - Herron to Stovall. Concerning intrigue of French Army officers and international financiers, 1918 December 22 (Item XXV)
    - Havas to Herron. Requesting transmission of a memorandum to President Wilson, 1918 December 23 (Item XXVI)
    - Herron to Havas, 1918 December 30 (Item XXVII)
    - Havas to Herron. Concerning official invitation to Hungary and Mme. Bédy-Schwimmer, 1918 December 31 (Item XXVIII)
    - Herron to Peace Commissioners, 1919 January 7 (Item XXIX)
    - Havas to Herron. Regarding census taken in Czechoslovakia; occupation of Northern Hungary, 1919 January 7 (Item XXX)
    - Havas to Herron, 1919 January 7 (Item XXX A)
    - Havas to Herron. Concerning visit to Hungary, 1919 January 8 (Item XXXI)
    - Herron to Havas. Concerning visit to Hungary (Item XXXI A)
    - Herron to Havas. Concerning Mr. Lansing's opinion of report which follows (Item XXXII)
    - Herron to Peace Commissioners, 1919 January 10 (Item XXXIII)
    - Dolbeare to Herron, 1919 January 16 (Item XXXIV)
    - Herron to Wilson, 1919 January 18 (Item XXXV)
    - Havas to Herron. Danger of Bolshevism in Hungary; need for immediate understanding of situation by Peace Conference, 1919 March 25 (Item XXXVI)
    - Herron to Havas. Concerning visit of Hungarian delegate to Paris, 1919 March 26 (Item XXXVII)
    - Herron to The President. Enclosing letter from Havas, 1919 March 26 (Item XXXVIII)
    - Herron to Sir W. Tyrell. Enclosing letter from Havas, 1919 March 29 (Item XXXIX)
    - Count Sigray to Herron. Enclosing memorandum on Hungarian situation, 1919 March 29 (Item XL)
    - Memorandum of Count Sigray, 1919 March 29 (Item XLI)
    - Herron to The President, 1919 March 31 (Item XLII)
    - Herron to Sir W. Tyrell, 1919 March 31 (Item XLIII)
    - Herron to The President, 1919 April 2 (Item XLIV)
    - Memorandum of Havas. Regarding Origin of Soviet Government in Hungary; means of action against Bolshevism, 1919 April 2 (Item XLV)
    - Herron to Dr. Dillon. Forwarding duplicates of documents about Russia and Hungary, 1919 April 4 (Item XLVI)
    - Havas to Herron. Concerning mission to Hungary, 1919 April 5 (Item XLVII)
    - Herron to Havas. Concerning Herron's appointment to Prinkipo, 1919 April 5 (Item XLVII A)
    - Sir W. Tyrell to Herron. Concerning Sigray Memorandum, 1919 April 14 (Item XLVIII)
    - Herron to Sigray. Regarding memorandum sent to President Wilson and Mr. Balfour; the latter's comments, 1919 April 22 (Item XLIX)
    - Herron to Sir W. Tyrell. Concerning Havas, 1919 April 22 (Item L)
    - Herron to Dulles. Same, 1919 April 22 (Item LI)
    - Dulles to Herron. Same, 1919 April 29 (Item LII)
    - Herron to Dulles. Same, 1919 April 30 (Item LIII)
    - Herron to Stovall. Same, 1919 May 1 (Item LIV)
    - Schiopul to Herron, 1919 September 11 (Item LV)
    - Herron to House. Enclosing preceding letter of Schiopul, 1919 September 13 (Item LVI)
    - A series of documents. (First in a free English translation and then in the French original.) Concerning relations of French army officers and financiers to the establishment of the Soviet Government in Hungary, 1919 September 11 (Item LVII)
    - Dr. Gerber to Herron. Enclosing document regarding interior conditions in Hungary, 1919 September 16 (Item LVIII)
    - Dr. Gerber to Herron. Memorandum regarding intervention of international financiers in Hungarian affairs; anti-semitic movement; danger of massacres, 1919 September 16 (Item LVIII A)
    - Dr. Gerber to Herron. Concerning restoration of Emperor Charles, 1919 September 18 (Item LIX)
    - Miss Vajkai to Herron, 1919 October 14 (Item LX)
    - Miss Vajkai to Herron. Report of Danish Vice Consul in Irkutsh, Siberia, of February 19, 1919. 1919 October 14 (Item LXI)
    - Herron to Miss Vajkai. Replying to above; regarding efforts already made and their failure; expressing sympathy, 1919 October 17 (Item LXII)
  - Volume VI. Italy
    - Herron to Marquis Paulucci di Calpoli. Commercial relations between Allies and Switzerland with special reference to Italy's refusal to allow food for cows to be exported, thereby causing a mild famine and compelling peasants to kill or sell cows - probably to Germany. 1916 December 19. See Switzerland Document VII (Item I)
    - Herron to Marquis Durezzo. American protests against Italy censoring Ambassadorial and Consular correspondence of her own Allies, 1917 January 3 (Item II)
    - Herron to Durezzo. American hostilities towards Italy, probably caused by interests of the Vatican, England, France and International finance; to be overcome by a new initiative of diplomacy open to the whole world; suggesting detailed program with regard to Serbia, Greece and Austria; and concerning possible visit of Mr. Herron to Rome, 1917 August 15 (Item III)
    - Herron to Durezzo. Italian statement to be made through American Press, and referring to the Adriatic question. Offering to write "An Appeal to Italy" for Italian paper. Dr. Caprin's papers and Genevese hostility to Italy, 1917 August 16 (Item IV)
    - Herron to Durezzo. Caporetto. Quoting opinions adverse to Italy said to have been given by Mr. Herron, 1917 December 27 (Item V)
    - Herron to Durezzo. Mr. F.F. Dumont and report that he had taken part in a dinner at which Kaiser's health was proposed; explaining what actually happened, and giving facts as to what he had been doing for Italy, 1917 December 29. (Item VI)
    - Herron to Hugh Wilson (Item VII)
    - Herron to Hugh Wilson. A second visit from Marquis Paulucci; presence of Dr. Field and Cdr. Whittall; Dr. Field's statement on mission of Lammasch; Paulucci's accidental meeting with Montgelas; his opinion of Sir Horace; visits of Whittall and Edwards, 1918 March 1 (Item VII A)
    - Duca di Cesarò to Herron. After Caporetto. Referring to report that Mr. Herron's sympathy for Italy has lessened. Acknowledging book, 1918 April 24 (Item VIII)
    - Herron to di Cesarò. Replying to above and explaining real position, 1918 May 24 (Item IX)
    - Herron to Mr. F.C. Walcott. Italian situation after Caporetto; German and Vatican preparation. Advising American or English troops for Italy. Frontier between Italy and Austria the vulnerable point of Central Empires, and also of Allies unless re-inforced. Regretting that League of Nations has not been convoked, 1918 September 13 (Item X)
    - Walcott to Herron. Acknowledging above. Referring to meeting with Marshal Foch and General Weygand; also Sir W. Tyrrell and Sir W. Goode and milk for Polish children, 1918 September 29 (Item XI)
    - Memorandum of Herron to State Department. Interior political situation of Italy. Strife between Orlando and Sonnino; relations with Yougo-Slavia and Austro-Hungary. Personnel of Italian Legation at Berne. Meeting between Foch and Orlando, and dispute between Orlando and Clemenceau. Possibility of finishing Austrian army on Italian Front, 1918 October 12 (Item XII)
    - Colonel R.J. MacHugh to Herron. Acknowledging copy of above memorandum and commenting on Clemenceau and the publication of Emperor Karl's letter, 1918 October 28. See Switzerland Document XIX, see Colonel MacHugh Document I (Item XIII)
    - Durezzo to Herron. Making appointment for interview with Baron Sonnino, 1919 January 27 (Item XIV)
    - Count Sforza to Herron. Making appointment, 1919 April 25 (Item XV)
    - Herron to Sir William Tyrrell. Enclosing letter from Ing. A. Coppo, 1919 May 7 (Item XVI)
    - Herron to President Woodrow Wilson. Enclosing letter from Ing. A. Coppo, 1919 May 7 (Item XVI A)
    - Ing. A. Coppo to Herron. Press campaign against Italy; French interests in Austro-Hungarian railways and in State Securities; Danubian Confederation, 1919 May 5. See The Peace - Dillon Document VII (Item XVI B)
    - Pasteur Ferrière to Herron. Letter enclosed on Austria and Italy, 1919 June 19 (Item XVII)
    - Pasteur Ferrière to Herron. Comments on Italy and Austria; affection for Italy and her necessity of an understanding with Austria, 1919 June 19 (Item XVIII)
    - Herron to Paulucci. Enclosing letter from Lammasch; Italy's opportunity for a new diplomatic initiative and relations with Austria, Hungary, Roumania and Czecho-Slovakia, 1919 June 19. See Roumania Document XIII - XVI (Item XIX)
    - Minister Orlando to Herron. Letter of greeting on taking up his residence in Berne. Possible personal relations with Herron, 1920 January 19 (Item XX)
    - Translation of above (Item XX A)
    - Herron to Orsini. Replying to preceding letter, 1920 January 23 (Item XXI)
    - Baron Acton to Herron. Acknowledging books and commenting on them, 1920 February 17 (Item XXII)
    - Herron to Acton. Replying to above; referring to President Wilson's intervention in Italy's questions and French hostility to Italy. Sonnino's conciliatory attitude, 1920 February 19 (Item XXIII)
    - Acton to Herron. Acknowledging above, 1920 February 22 (Item XXIV)
    - Herron to Acton. Enclosing letter from Mr. C.W. Barron; possible visit to Italy, 1920 February 25 (Item XXV)
    - Herron to Acton. Telephone call from Italian Minister, 1920 February 26 (Item XXVI)
    - Orsini to Herron. Acknowledging letters of February 26 and 27, 1920 March 5 (Item XXVII)
    - Orsini to Herron. Enclosing introduction for Count Sforza and 'laissez-passer,' 1920 March 20 (Item XXVIII)
    - Herron to Acton. After visit in Italy; private audience with King of Italy and interview with Count Sforza, 1920 April 14 (Item XXIX)
    - Herron to Orsini. After visit to Italy - her hopeful prospects; private audience with King; invitation to Geneva, 1920 April 14 (Item XXX)
    - Orsini to Herron. Acknowledging above, 1920 April 16 (Item XXXI)
    - Herron to Dr. Comnène. Giving impressions of Italy; her relations with Roumania; her evolution; impression of Count Sforza; d'Annunzio; private audience with the King, 1920 April 26. See Roumania Document XLII and XLIII (Item XXXII)
    - Herron to Orsini. Death of Professor Karmin; asking for work for his wife, 1920 June 5 (Item XXXIII)
    - Herron to Orsini. Request to convey to H.M. the King Herron's thanks for honour conferred upon him; the world's high esteem of His Majesty, 1920 June 12 (Item XXXIV)
    - Herron to Sforza. His appointment as Minister of Foreign affairs; future of Italy, 1920 June 14 (Item XXXV)
    - Herron to Sforza. Renaissance of war-time propaganda in Switzerland in bureaux of Czecho-Slovakia, Persia, Macedonia, Crimea, Bulgaria, Egypt and Russia; Britain friendly to Italy, France unfriendly; asking what is Italy's attitude toward Macedonia, Albania and Russia, 1920 June 18 (Item XXXVI)
    - Sforza to Herron. Acknowledging letter of June 14, 1920 June 18 (Item XXXVII)
    - Herron to the King of Italy. Thanking him for Honour; expressing appreciation of the King's conduct during war and peace negotiations; Italy's promising future, 1920 June 20 (Item XXXVIII)
    - Herron to Acton. Enclosing a note, 1920 June 23 (Item XXXIX)
    - Acton to Herron. Enclosing Count Sforza's reply to letter of June 18, 1920 July 22 (Item XL)
    - Herron to Acton. Enclosing letter concerning the "Agence Centrale," 1920 July 28 (Item XLI)
    - Herron to Acton. Purchase of the "Agence Centrale" by the French Government; Dr. Bessemer's appointment and antecedents; French plans for Danubian Confederations and restoration of Hapsburgs; news service used to prevent union of Austria with Germany; detachment of Bavaria from Germany and its union with Austria; to establish supremacy of France in S.E. Europe and Balkans; to divide Italy and Roumania and generally to decry Italy, 1920 July 28 (Item XLII)
    - Orsini to Herron. Acknowledging copy of "Auslandspost," 1920 September 22 (Item XLIII)
    - Herron to Acton. Asking for diploma of decoration; forwarding second copy of "Nation" for use of the King, 1920 September 28 (Item XLIV)
    - Acton to Herron. Acknowledging letters of September 28 and October 1; forwarding "A New Italian Renaissance" to the King, 1920 October 2 (Item XLV)
    - Herron to Acton. Enclosing cutting on France's action with regard to Bavaria, 1920 October 4 (Item XLVI)
    - Herron to Orsini. Request to forward letter to Sforza, enclosing a duplicate. Herron's departure for Italy, 1920 October 19 (Item XLVII)
    - Herron to Sforza. "Oxford University Press" to issue their "World Series"; Herron to write one on Italy; request to put him in connection with rapid investigations in Italy; two sources of evil to Italy - Bolshevist influences and international capitalists and bankers; they will assault her shipping and commerce; Wilson's failure; centre of world will be Rome, 1920 October 19 (Item XLVII A)
    - Herron to Cav. U. Rochira. Appreciation of Herron's article in "The New Republic"; quoting extracts from above letter on two sources of evil to Italy, 1920 October 25 (Item XLVIII)
    - Orsini to Herron. Acknowledging letter of 19th; also receipt of Herron's publication on the Treaty of Versailles, 1920 November 2 (Item XLIX)
    - Orsini to Herron. Enclosing diploma of decoration, 1920 November 3 (Item L)
    - Herron to Orsini. Acknowledging above and departure for Italy, 1920 November 4 (Item LI)
    - Orsini to Herron. Assuring him that letter for Sforza will be forwarded by next courier, 1920 November 4 (Item LII)
    - Orsini to Herron. Conveying the interest of the King of Italy in Herron's article on the new renaissance in Italy, 1920 November 6 (Item LIII)
    - Sforza to Herron. Acknowledging copy of letter sent to the American Ambassador in Peking, 1920 November 17 (Item LIV)
    - Sforza to Herron. Thanking him for kind words and congratulations; Cavour mentioned, 1920 December 28 (Item LV)
    - Orsini to Herron. Concerning Herron's visit to Italy; Sforza notified to be at his disposal for information required for compiling of book; desire for the return of his good health, 1921 February 4 (Item LVI)
    - Sforza to Herron. Appointment with Minister Croce at the Ministry of Public Instruction; suggesting interview with Giolitti, 1921 February 10 (Item LVII)
    - Sforza to Herron. Above appointment postponed, 1921 February 10 (Item LVIII)
    - Sforza to Herron. Appointment with Turati, Senator Loria, Senator Schanzer, Senator Rinaudi and Professor H. Backi; Dr. Mattoli will arrange for one with Giolitti, 1921 February 11 (Item LVIX)
    - Sforza to Herron. Quiet week-end out of town; acknowledging letter of yesterday, 1921 February 15 (Item LX)
    - Herron to Orsini. Request to forward enclosed letter to Sforza; conversations with Giolitti and other members of the Government; Florentine troubles; confidence in Italy, 1921 March 17 (Item LXI)
    - Herron to Sforza. Concerning the moral tragedy of Sforza's position; commenting on it; fascisti and bolshevists in Florence; request for confidential explanation of Count Karoly's affair; his interviews of 1917; several remarks on Hungarian question and French plot to re-establish Hapsbourgs; introductions for Jazzi; request for definite proofs of Karoly's complicity with Bolshevists, 1921 March 17 (Item LXI A)
    - Orsini to Herron. Felicitations at Herron's return to Geneva. In Italian, 1921 March 18 (Item LXII)
    - Count M. Karoly to Herron. Concerning his arrest and expulsion from Italy; giving full facts of the case; his desire to obtain permission to reside in a neutral country; Dr. Paul Szende, 1921 March 22 (Item LXIII)
    - Enclosure to above. Declaration of Count Karoly; his determined negation of all reasons for his expulsion; giving detailed proofs; claiming satisfaction. In French (Item LXIII A)
    - Enclosure to above. Declaration of Count Karoly. In German (Item LXIII B)
    - Sforza to Herron. Concerning difficulty of altering Count Karoly's situation; chiefly due to troubles in Florence, 1921 March 25 (Item LXIV)
    - Herron to Sforza. Acknowledging above; urging importance of Viviani's visit to America; President Harding's pronouncement regarding Russia and French Foreign policy; American policy based on fundamental antagonism to England; bent upon commercial supremacy and mastery of the seas; capitalistic and perilous to the world; American finance means to occupy Mexico and destroy Japan; Italy's safety lies in sticking to England and support her in a liberal policy; Italy may be a connecting link between England, Germany and Russia; French policy is to encroach upon Germany from the west and urge Poland to do the same on the east, which will be final ruin of Europe; supporting Giolitti, 1921 March 28 (Item LXV)
    - Herron to Sforza. Enclosing copy of letter and declarations from Count Karoly; suggesting rectification for Italy's good, 1921 March 29 (Item LXVI)
    - Herron to Karoly. Assuring him of Herron's efforts towards obtaining his rectification; reaction in America and mob violence, 1921 March 29 (Item LXVII)
    - Orsini to Herron. Giving assurance of the forwarding of letter to Sforza. In Italian, 1921 March 30 (Item LXVIII)
    - Herron to Sforza. Concerning veracity of Kaiser Karl's statement on arrival at Steinamanger; Count Karoly's conversations on this; his bitter feeling against Bolshevist regime of Bela Khun in Hungary; Professor Jazzi; Count Andrassi; refuge for Karoly in Italy, Trentino, Capri, or Tripoli, 1921 April 1 (Item LXIX)
    - Herron to Sforza. Suggestion of giving a diplomatic appointment to Baron Acton; his devoted services in Geneva; suggesting Bulgaria or Angora, 1921 April 1 (Item LXX)
    - Sforza to Herron. Replying favourably to the above, 1921 April 7 (Item LXXI)
    - Sforza to Herron. Acknowledging letters about Count Karoly; difficulty of coming to a different decision; his books will be returned through Senator Vigliani, 1921 April 9 (Item LXXII)